<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <link>http://localhost:4000</link>
    <description>
      Welcome to my little corner of the internet.
    </description>
    
        
            <item>
                <title>I'll be Everything</title>
                <link>http://localhost:4000/everything</link>
                <content:encoded>
                    <![CDATA[
                    <p>It was not too long ago that I realized something - Life is long.</p>

<p>Now, it was a very odd realization. I tried to fight it. Maybe it seems long because you don’t have anything to do, I said to myself. But it was not true. I barely have time to think these days.</p>

<p>And most people complain about that too. Not having enough time. There is nothing in the world I hate more than my need to sleep. And it seems to me that a lot of people feel the same. That is why almost every motivational quote emphasizes the importance of time. Life is too short, they say.</p>

<p>I’m 22 right now. I hope I live at least 40 more years. That is twice the time I’ve lived. There’s a scary thought - I’ve lived through one third of my life, and that is if I’m lucky.</p>

<p>But then I think about these 22 years - all the things I’ve learnt, the fun I’ve had, the memories I’ve made. And I can do two times more the stuff I’ve done. Possibly more, if I spend my time wisely.</p>

<p>‘Life is short’ - I think it all comes down to how you interpret these words. If you take them at face value, it means there are only are few things that you’ll get to do. So pick wisely. And from what I’ve seen, there are two choices - pick one or two things, get really good at them, and maybe if you religiously devote your life to those, you’ll achieve something magical, and hope that the world recognizes that magic, preferably while you are alive.</p>

<p>Now, some really brilliant people have managed to create magic in more than a couple of fields. And I think that’s something really rare, and not really whithin the reach of most people.</p>

<p>But the gold standard, what society tells you, is that you pick a field - ideally something you are “passionate” about - and get so good that people pay you to practice it. The earlier in your life you start, the better. And that becomes your living. And maybe then, you have some chance of creating some magic.</p>

<p>Then you take care of other people - your family, and hope that your children will also follow your way of life. And that becomes the dream for most people (including me, until a little while ago). And there is nothing wrong with that, if you are the kind of person who can devote his life to a single thing.</p>

<p>But I’m not. And I used to beat myself up for it. People who cared about me would be frustrated, and furious that I can’t seem to be able to stick to a thing. And that used to make me frustrated and sad. If I continue like this, I’ll never be able to make it to the gold standard. What will I do with my life? I’ve tried hard to answer this question but to no avail.</p>

<p>But there’s a second choice, and a second, slightly different interpretation of the words ‘Life is short’. For me these words mean that if you don’t actively participate in your own life, it will seem short to you. That means you have to be more than just the observer. You have to be at the cause. You have to stop other people from controlling your life. And its difficult. It is difficult to stop letting other people dictate your life because you are too used to it. I was too used to it.</p>

<p>So the first thing I did was to stop putting the blame on others. Even if it actually was their fault, I would take the blame on myself. That empowered me. If you blame other people, you can’t solve the problem, because you take the power out of your hands. And that also helped me to take better decisions. Because I knew that I would later blame myself if anything goes wrong, I took the responsibility to do things I wanted.</p>

<p>It sounds selfish, and it is. Because the most important person for me, is me.</p>

<p>And now, all of a sudden, life seems long to me. Because I actively participate in it. I want to do a lot of things. I want to be a lot of things. It used to make me sad because I thought I won’t be able to. But now, I’ve come to know that if I’m willing to let go of the gold standard, to let go of the possibility of creating magic, I get to ask the questiom: why not all?</p>

<p>Why can’t I be everything I want and more? The old ansewer was “life is short”. But I think its the mindset that is short. And I used to operate in the short-term mindset. But now, when I dream about me being something new, I collect everything and push it to a folder.</p>

<p>I’ll pick it up later.</p>

<p>I’ll be everything, just not at the same time.</p>

                    ]]>
                </content:encoded>
                <guid isPermaLink="false">/everything</guid>
                <description>
                    
                    It was not too long ago that I realized something - Life is long.
                    
                </description>
                <pubDate>Mon, 03 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
                <author>Parav Singla</author>
            </item>
        
    
        
            <item>
                <title>Practice</title>
                <link>http://localhost:4000/practice</link>
                <content:encoded>
                    <![CDATA[
                    <p>“This is something you’ll learn only by practice. And it’ll only stay with you as long as you keep practicing”.</p>

<p>An old man said this to me once. I asked him how I could improve my sketches. I didn’t really pay attention to his words at the time. I thought he was spouting the same bullshit everyone says. It sounded to me like a truism.</p>

<p>Recently, I was sifting through my stuff and I found my old sketchbook. Memories came rushing back to me when I went through the pages. A few sketches were so good that I couldn’t believe I had done them. And it made me sad.</p>

<p>Then I searched for my old diary, where I used to write my poems. Again, a few of them were brilliant. They were definitely written by someone else. I felt like a sham. A shadow of my former self.</p>

<p>I couldn’t remember why I gave it up, but it was probably because at some point of time, I must’ve thought this wasn’t the best way I could make use of my time. And then I thought of everything else I had given up because I felt it was useless. Foreign languages, painting, music, sports - I gave up all of them. How can I die a happy man if they haunt me on my deathbed?</p>

<p>In Oscar Wilde’s introduction to THE PICTURE OF DORIAN GRAY, he says, “All art is quite useless.”. In my quest to become more productive, I let go of everything I deemed useless. I never thought that I would need to feed my soul too, along with my thoughts. I never thought I would need some me-time.</p>

<p>I have started again, from scratch. I realise the weight in the words of the old man now.</p>

                    ]]>
                </content:encoded>
                <guid isPermaLink="false">/practice</guid>
                <description>
                    
                    This is something you'll learn only by practice. And it'll only stay with you as long as you keep practicing...
                    
                </description>
                <pubDate>Tue, 28 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
                <author>Parav Singla</author>
            </item>
        
    
        
            <item>
                <title>None of this will Matter</title>
                <link>http://localhost:4000/matter</link>
                <content:encoded>
                    <![CDATA[
                    <p>It was October of 2014.</p>

<p>I was in my first year in the university. Me and my friends were carrying this really heavy robot(if you could call it that) that we had created for competing in a competition called Robowars.</p>

<p>We were spent - both mentally and physically. It was not the transportation of that chunk of metal that had exhausted us. We had just been through the first round of the competition. And I couldn’t believe that we’d won. I couldn’t will my legs to stop shaking.</p>

<p>We stopped in the middle of road that led to the hostels to catch our breath. I was barely functional. This was the most exhilarating experience I had ever had in my life. I was trying to calm myself down. It felt like my heart would explode. I was overcome by a plethora of emotions. We had just started this for fun. My friend, who was to control the bot, only had a couple of hours of practice.</p>

<p>I was a kid who came from a town with a population of 50,000. In India, that makes for a very small town. My high school class had a strength of 40. I made it to state level in sports and ten people knew about it. My facebook profile picture had 9 likes on it, and that was back when facebook was the cool thing.</p>

<p>And Bam! a couple months later, the same kid whom nobody had given a shit about his whole life was standing in an arena surrounded by at least a couple hundred people, all chanting the name of his team. Why wouldn’t it be the most exhilarating experience of his life.</p>

<p>We were setting up the bot, doing a precursory check. Our opponents were final year students. They were calm. It looked like they meant business. It was then I noticed that he hadn’t anticipated this crowd too. He was shaking more than me. I offered to control the bot. He hesitantly handed me the controller. I used the same trick to calm myself down that I use everytime. “None of this will matter in a few years”, I told to myself. “Nobody will remember how bad you sucked.”</p>

<p>But its hard to convince yourself that when there are hundreds of people chanting the name of your team and your college. Home crowd ‘advantage’. I mess up even my favorite songs if I have to play them for people to this date. So no doubt, I sucked pretty bad. Regardless, we had won. And since we wouldn’t stop shouting after the match, they kicked us out of there. So there we were - in the middle of the road, our bodies shaking, and our heads still trying to process what had happened.</p>

<p>A guy approached us, asking for a picture. I looked at my friend. We thought he was from another college. We somehow managed to pose for a decent photograph. We talked for a while and then while leaving, we exchanged names. His sounded vaguely familiar, but I didn’t care.</p>

<p>A friend of mine who had seen us later told me that the guy was an alumnus, and he was somebody.</p>

<p>It is 2018 now. Almost four years have passed since the day, but I remember it like it was yesterday. At some point between now and then, I abandoned the aforementioned technique to calm myself down. Because the truth is, while nobody did remember how bad I sucked (except my friends), it has been a few years and it still matters.</p>

<p>It mattered to me then, and it matters to me now. And it matters not because I spent months working on that robot, or because it was the first time I had experienced something like it, though these are perfectly valid reasons. It matters because even though now I live in a city with a population of 12 million, the corporation I work for employs 250,000 people, and I have more than 9 likes on my facebook profile picture, I’m still that kid.</p>

<p>“This is a moment that you’ll remember for a long, long time. Let’s make the best out of it.” is what I say to myself nowadays.</p>

                    ]]>
                </content:encoded>
                <guid isPermaLink="false">/matter</guid>
                <description>
                    
                    It was October of 2014. I was in my first year in the university. Me and my friends were carrying this really heavy...
                    
                </description>
                <pubDate>Tue, 21 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
                <author>Parav Singla</author>
            </item>
        
    
  </channel>
</rss>
